# **Jacob Cox**

Full Stack Software Developer

Solutions-driven Software Developer with 10+ years of project management experience in the Manufacturing sector where my organizational skills helped realize a four-fold increase in sales during my tenure. Proficient in JavaScript and Python as well as relational and non-relational databases. Dedicated to empowering clients and personnel to dream big, but iteratively.

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

#### **GIMME5**

**Tools**: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, Express, MongoDB, Sentencer, Heroku

**Overview**: Exercise app for writers, guiding them through a series of writing prompts. Users ideas are stored and later drawn upon to generate the first draft of a project.

## THE LONG RUN

**Tools**: JavaScript, Express, MongoDB, Bootstrap, React, Strava API, Oauth, Heroku

**Overview**: Marathon training app that generates workouts based on the user's skill level, keeping track of distance, time, weather, and any personal notes the user adds. A progress bar tracks the miles logged as they aim for their targeted race-day goal.

## **STOCK APP**

**Tools**: JavaScript, Express, MongoDB, Skeleton, React, Yahoo Finance API, SEC API

**Overview**: Stock tracking app that allows a user to research stocks and build a stored portfolio "watch list". Price targets can be stored with the user being alerted when they hit.

Chicago, IL (612) 916-5253

jacob@championofvictory.com

LinkedIn: <u>Jacob-Joseph-Cox</u>

GitHub: cox512

## **SKILLS**

JavaScript/Node.js, Python, Flask, HTML, CSS, SQLite, JQuery, React, Mongoose, Bootstrap, EJS, Express.js, APIs, MVC, OOP, Excel, MongoDB, Git/Github, Bash, AJAX, Heroku

## **EDUCATION**

# **General Assembly**

Software Engineering Fellow 500 + hour training program focused on Git/Github, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, MongoDB, SQL, Python, and React

# **Lawrence University**

Appleton, WI BA Studio Art magna cum laude

## SELECTED EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

## Banquet Captain/Server | Lettuce Entertain You | Chicago, IL | 2016-present

Oversee the planning and execution of small and large-scale corporate events and private parties ranging in size from 20 to 520.

- · Organized a crew of team members from a variety of backgrounds to work as a single unit by laying out a cohesive vision for all events and clearly delineating duties
- · Able to adapt to an ever-changing set of circumstances, re-orchestrating the assignments of team members on the fly to seamlessly transition from the old plan to the new

# Keith Clayton Furniture | Chicago, IL | Project Manager | 2005-2016

Created joyful handmade furnishings for an array of clientele. Lead a team of motivated artisans to achieve quick turnaround while maintaining product integrity.

- · Accomplished a 300+% increase in sales during my tenure without the use of paid advertising
- Engaged entire build team in the project-planning process, elevating their personal stakes and improving product quality while minimizing costly communication lapses, resulting in a large upswing in repeat business and word-of-mouth recommendations
- · Organized and streamlined the budgeting, scheduling, production, and installation process to make best use of facility space and decrease the need for a costly expansion

## Freelance Playwright | Chicago, IL | 2010-present

Award-winning, internationally produced writer of short and long-form plays. In charge of crafting the vision, goals, and development strategy for dozens of rehearsal settings.

- · Directed a crew of nearly 20 collaborators over a month-long film shoot, finishing production ahead of schedule
- · Lead conductor of the years-long play creation process from initial concept and script generation, through the multi-tiered workshopping system, and into production

# Fig Media | Chicago, IL | Video Editor | 2005-2006

Collaborated with a team of Producers and Videographers to generate personal documentaries as well as slick corporate promotions using Final Cut Pro.

- · Worked hand-in-hand with clients in crafting a meticulous product, translating feedback into clearly articulated and actionable steps for the larger team.
- · Quickly learned and implemented new graphic and motion software into my daily workflow.
- · Educated a team of Editors in Adobe After Effects and guided them through the creation of a multi-media corporate marketing presentation at a local planetarium.